foreign
just because I got a lot of messages
uh that due to uh Diwali Festival uh if
you could postpone the class it would be
better for all of us that's why I had
postponed otherwise there was no other
reason
okay so uh now today and tomorrow we
will have class and next week also again
uh we will have class on Saturday Sunday
as communicated to you all of you are
getting my voice right yes yes yes
so uh today uh we are going to uh learn
three strategies and all these three
strategies are chart pattern based
strategies not on technical indicators
so our technical indicators and chart
patterns both are different things like
uh moving average is a technical
indicator and Knoxville uh is also a
technical indicator however uh this
reverse head and shoulder pattern and
cuff with handle powder it won't be all
these are the chart pattern based uh
technical it means trading strategies so
uh today we are going to learn three uh
first of all we will start with the
reverse head and shoulder pattern that
is the most common one I do usually use
uh in all of my videos uh most of the
time however here we will learn uh in
step by step manner that what we need to
do and what we don't need to do what we
need to escape and on which company we
need to apply it how much percentage of
the total portfolio uh we should invest
in uh one stock again based on this
strategy
right so uh because in a lot of
technical uh analysis book this strategy
has been taught in a uh I would say in a
wrong manner uh we need to uh filter out
a lot more things before applying this
reverse head and shoulder pattern on any
of the stock see uh one thing we need to
remember
uh any technical strategy will not work
if the company is not a good company
right we need to remember this
so we need to uh stay away from any
company that is not a good company in
terms of the business and in terms of
the financial stability
right so how to identify a business I
have already taught you uh that uh
the dense means
the penetration of the product should
not be at the peak uh means the per
capita uses of that product should be at
the lower end as we had uh searched on
Google that how many cars we do have per
1000 people and how much percentage we
are spending on medical expenses uh how
many uh people are having home now and
how many are going to have going forward
so uh this is a very general uh sense
and we can search on Google that whether
this business is going to prosper going
forward or not whether we are going to
have a good demand uh going forward
right and as far as Financial stability
is concerned uh we will be uh learning
this tomorrow uh tomorrow the complete
session will be on our financials that
what we need to have a look at uh while
doing financial analysis and what we
need to escape
right so tomorrow the complete session
will be on uh financial analysis which
is called the fundamental analysis so
people do call this fundamental analysis
uh however fundamental analysis means
the business analysis and balance sheet
analysis means the financial analysis
but uh means almost everyone is skipping
this business analysis which is much
more important
right we need to understand this
so uh today as I told you uh we should
use any of the strategy only on the good
companies good companies the definition
we have already defined like v40
companies v40 next and v200 companies we
don't need to go outside we uh 40 v40
next and we 200 companies to trade
actually
there's no need and all of these
strategies are not being applied on all
the uh group of companies as I uh told
you in previous session T20 strategy is
not T20 v20 strategy is applicable on
v200 companies on v200 companies v40 and
v40 next however moving average strategy
is applicable on uh v40 companies only
and Knoxville is also applicable only on
v40 campaigns right we do we do remember
all this uh and I hope all of you have
gone through the classes once again uh
in last few days uh just to revise the
classes is utmost important we need to
revise the classes many times
because we don't need to have a look at
the notepad again and again while taking
the trades all these learning should be
in our subconscious mind all this
learning should be in our memory
right
so uh this reverse head and shoulder
pattern we will call it rhs
rhs reverse head and shoulder pattern
generally uh a lot of people call it
head and shoulder pattern and
so head and shoulder pattern usually uh
we are we do apply only when the stock
price uh is targeted to be going down
when the stock price is supposed to go
down then we use head and shoulder
pattern however we will use reverse head
and shoulder pattern when we are uh
targeting for the stock to go up so
reverse means the inverse a lot of
people call it inverse head and shoulder
pattern as well so inverse and reverse
both are the same thing
so let me show you on the chart that how
to uh do this and how to analyze this
can you see the screen please
yeah
so uh
I'll just
so this is the clean board now to
understand
I'm taking the brush
so this is the left shoulder
right and this is the head
and this is the right shoulder
so this is called the this is called the
head and shoulder pattern and this is
the neckline
this is the head and shoulder pattern
this is the head this one is the head
this is head this is shoulder
and
sorry
I'm sorry this is shorter this is head
and this is shoulder
right so this is just like a human as
I'm we can see and this is the neckline
so this neckline uh this uh horizontal
line is the neckline and this neckline
should be connected uh with the
both sides of the head and
the Inception of the left shoulder this
is the proper head and shoulder pattern
however we will not be using it we will
be using reverse head and shoulder
pattern like
this is the left shoulder
this is the head
and this is the right shoulder
okay
and this is the neckline
so this is the correct one this is the
I'm taking the brush this is the
shoulder
this is head
and this is the right shoulder
so uh in this reverse head and shoulder
pattern there are three connecting
points
first Connecting Point is uh this one
the starting of the left shoulder second
Connecting Point is the end of the right
end of the first shoulder means the left
shoulder and starting of the head
third Connecting Point is end of the
head and starting of the right shoulder
so there are three connecting points at
the same level
and these three connecting points should
be connected at the horizontal line 180
degree line
always remember it should be on the
horizontal line
a lot of people teach like it could be
in upward Trend it could be in doubt and
uh downward Trend that is wrong
that is absolutely wrong so if we call
that this is the left shoulder and this
is the head and this is the right
shoulder right and this is the neckline
connecting uh three points however this
neckline is the uptrending line so this
is wrong
this is not the correct one
this is wrong why this is wrong because
here the connecting points are one
Connecting Point is at this level second
Connecting Point is another up level and
third Connecting Point is another up
level it means these three levels are
different levels and
here could be different operator here
could be different operator and here
could be different operator
means the seller somewhere the seller
Big Time seller could be different here
it could be different here it could be
different here because levels are
different levels
however when these connecting points are
at the same level it means this is the
same seller this is the same seller and
this is the same seller means operator
is same here
okay in the same manner if this is
downtrending means this is the left
shoulder this is the head and this is
the right shoulder and neckline is down
trending line
neckline is down trending line
connecting three points again there is
no difference in connecting points one
Connecting Point second Connecting Point
third Connecting Point however the
neckline is a reclining this is on the
downtrend this is not the correct one
because here the operator could be
different here operator could be
different and here operator could be
different
all this is operators game means every
chart pattern is being built up by
operators
with the help of their buying and
selling and with the specific intention
I will teach you how
and all these patterns are getting built
up only when the price is coming down
so price to come down is necessary to
have a
specific chart pattern if the price is
not coming down we will not be able to
see any chart pattern and we won't be
able to trade based on the technical
chart pattern
so uh when the price is coming down this
is in our favor without technical chart
patterns without uh price to come down
we cannot use technical analysis
are you getting a point so uh
if the price is going down it's
important this is necessary this is
necessary for everyone
this is necessary for everyone
I don't know why people are very uh less
today or only 42 participants whereas
the last time this was uh 72 are they
angry
ah
many uh I have just opened your voice
you can unmute and we can talk for two
minutes if uh I think they are all they
all need more time to digest the sweets
since I think that they have not a
proper schedule of the class
once you uh you should send a message in
that WhatsApp bro
no this was uh means it was communicated
properly yeah yeah
was there uh to reply each and every
message so I I don't think any of the
question was unanswered during this
period uh maybe a pre-planned a vacation
today we have a class
[Music]
40 are not here 40 percent
ages but the thing is actually the same
thing the the I think there was no
proper reminder and because of this
festive season and all people scripted I
believe but probably yeah it could be
due to festive season and uh anyways
this weekend we were uh supposed to have
the class uh this this weekend we were
supposed to have the class in any way
yes yes yes yes yes yes you are right
right it was planned earlier itself
actually uh I know uh what happened uh
means I am guessing it because uh all of
us are getting uh recording uh in the
next next day in the morning so
nobody wants that is the primary reason
yes and this is Saturday night so
Saturday night usually after Diwali a
lot of us could be having liquor and all
uh
Party Time
weekend might be anything there could be
any reason but I would love to get the
feedback if uh something anything
happened wrong my side I just received
it uh because of I get a lot of messages
from uh the participants the
participants otherwise uh I can tell you
yesterday it was my birthday and I went
oh happy birthday sir thank you belated
happy birthday thank you thank you
brother so I went to rishikesh
means uh to uh visit uh neelkanth
Mahadev mandir and uh today itself I
came back so in two days I I have driven
the car for almost 600 kilometers I was
tired but I I didn't reschedule just
because of my own reason last week I had
rescheduled this because I have a lot of
requests from uh
there was a wise moves up that was a
very wise move because Diwali and all
that it's very important that you it's
good that you rescheduled it exactly
because a lot of people uh were coming
everybody's home to meet and greet to
wish Diwali uh anyways it's is okay one
more participants went off uh so now 41
I don't know
maybe connectivity issue might be might
be but if
if any means uh this is being recorded
and uh all of us will be getting this
recorded uh session as well so if
anything happened uh wrong at my side
and if anybody is angry then please
excuse me uh no I would say uh
uh
there's something like that okay yeah
yeah let's continue it yeah so let's
continue
we will open the chat again after
completing the session means in next one
and half an hour I will complete three
strategies and later on we will discuss
we will have q a on that we will talk
dance right so let's start again yes
so uh I was saying uh
these uh vertical lines means connecting
points should be uh just horizontal it
could not it should not be on the
uptrend like this uh and it should not
be on the downtrend like this but in a
lot of technical analysis book it has
been taught like uh it could be obtained
what means it could be obtained uh
connecting a line or it could be
downtrend connecting line uh according
to my according to my experience we do
get uh very mediocre result if we are
using uptrend or downtrend connecting
line however if you are using uh just
horizontal 180 degree uh line we are
getting better results
now second point is we will be using
this strategy reverse head and shoulder
pattern only on v40 and v40 next
companies
we will be using reverse head and
shoulder pattern only in v40 and v40
next companies it means we will have 80
companies to use this strategy
right we will have 180 companies
880 companies to use this strategy and
uh
we will invest three percent of the
total portfolio in one stock again
there is no stop loss
there's noise stop loss
uh this is an optional uh that I do
recommend if
the
probable gain is more than 40 then we
should use this strategy
you can make a note of it it's
recommended if uh the potential gain is
uh 40 plus
then we should use this strategy
so that in a single trade we could we
could have 40 plus gain means uh the
annual Target
could be achieved in just one trade
it will help us when we are in corporate
life and we don't have too much time to
trade on daily basis
very frequently it will help us
so if we could get 10 trades based on
reverse head and shoulder pattern
having potential gain of more than 40
percent it means 33 percent of the
capital would be invested for just one
trade a year
right so this is very uh beneficial for
people who are having very less time to
study the stocks
but if we have time we can analyze
stocks on weekly basis means this is uh
applicable on all the stocks where
potential gain is less than 40 percent
so uh I will teach you how to get how to
get the potential gain how to uh measure
that so uh first of all we need to
identify a stock
which is having three connecting points
at the same level
at the same level and we will not use
head and shoulder pattern any time in
the life we will never be using this
particular pattern that is the head and
shoulder pattern because head and
shoulder pattern is suggesting the price
to go down
we are not
so shorting any stock we are not selling
it first we are not trading in fndo we
are not doing intraday that's why
we have one option to buy and sell
letter says sell it later right we don't
have any option
so uh we will be using reverse head and
shoulder pattern only
no head and shoulder pattern only
reverse head and shoulder pattern I am
taking an example here Reliance
Industries
so Reliance Industries there was a uh
head and shoulder pattern here
right few things we need to note down
as uh I had made a pattern like uh this
is the
shoulder
this is one more shoulder
this is the head
this is the right shoulder and this is
one more small shoulder
so we need to note down there could be
more than one shoulder on either side
there could be more than one shoulder on
either side
so this is shoulder one
this is shoulder two
this is head
this is right shoulder
one
and this is right
shoulder two
right
this is the left shoulder one
this is left shoulder two
this is head this is right shoulder one
and right shoulder two
there could be more shoulder on either
side it it could be like on the left
hand side there is one shoulder on the
right hand side there are two shoulders
it is also possible
it is also possible that on the left
hand side there are two solders and on
the right hand side there is one
shoulder
there could be more than one shoulder on
either side the depth and width of
shoulders
could vary it could be different
so all the shoulders could be of
different shape
all these shoulders
could be of different shape
right
however the depth of shoulder could not
be deeper than head
the depth of the shoulder should not be
deeper than
head
okay
so uh wherever we are having more than
one shoulder on either side this is
called complex head and shoulder pattern
complex reverse head and shoulder
pattern when we have more than one
shoulder on either side
this is called complex reverse head and
shoulder pattern
complex reverse head and shoulder
pattern has more significance
then normal reverse head and shoulder
pattern it means if we are having more
shoulders than one
then this is a much better chart pattern
in terms of hitting the target
this is more reliable
right so uh to measure the target
we need to measure the depth depth means
the lowest point of the head
till
neckline we need to measure from the
lowest
level of the head till neckline and
during doing this we need to make sure
that this chart is not a log chart it
should be non-log chart normal chart
means on the right hand side lower
bottom
there is an icon log if we click this it
will turn blue if we click it again it
will turn black
so we need to deselect log
it should be normal chart it should not
be a log chart please note it down
okay
it should be a normal chart not a log
chart
and we need to pick this dap this
measurement and place it on the
horizontal connecting line which is
called the neckline
and it will become the target
and this target was achieved
very soon now
and after hitting this target the same
price did not come even after 10 months
it is started coming down
now
where is the buying point
we need to see a few connecting points
means connecting points of shoulders
and the end of the head
and the beginning of the right shoulder
so right shoulder we will see
a base formation
and the breakout from this base
formation so what do we mean by base
formation they are
three steps in shoulder one step is the
price is coming down second step is
price is
trading in a Range
and third is price has started moving up
this is like the wheel of the car
the wheel started coming down
it is stopped going down and it was flat
and then it took a U-turn so it's like a
u
right first it was going down it was
trading in a range and it started moving
out
so we need to see where it stopped going
down
and it made a range
and from this range it should start
moving up
so the moment is it start moving up we
will be buying
so to identifying a range is very easy
for example
and removing all the
drawings and placing only
horizontal line the connecting line
right
so we have identified here few things
like the starting point of shoulder and
point of shoulder then head then right
shoulder and this is a deeper one and
this point
so up to this point we have come to know
that this is a shape of reverse head and
shoulder pattern means left shoulders
and a big head and it is going down
however we will be buying only when
there is a right shoulder information
base formation and breakout with green
candle on closing basis please note it
down
the buying point is
at the Breakout
with green candle
the buying point is at the Breakout
on closing basis
there are three steps
breakout with green candle on closing
basis from the base formation
of the right shoulder
so steps in their Steps step number one
break out please note it down break out
plus green candle
just note it down break out plus green
candle plus closing basis
breakout plus green candle plus closing
basis
from plus from
base formation
Plus
on the right shoulder
so there are five things to uh have a
look at number one
right shoulder
then base formation then break out then
green candle then closing basis Five
Points
right there are five points
and in case we have more than one
shoulder we will be doing this exercise
on the first shoulder itself because we
don't know if second shoulder will be
made or not
right so we will be doing it
at the first shoulder itself because we
don't know whether second shoulder will
be made or not
so first step is to identify three four
connecting points up to end of the head
right and these connecting points should
be just horizontal 180 degree just flat
so beginning of the shoulders end of the
shoulders end of the shoulders means the
beginning of the head
and end of the head end of the head
means the beginning of the right
shoulder
right
and after beginning of the right
shoulder it should start coming down
it should start coming down to
building up the right shoulder
and right shoulder will be confirmed
only if it is being Consolidated in a
Range to made a base
when it is starting to consolidate in a
Range to make a base and a breakout on
closing basis with green candle
so that time it will be confirmed that
this right shoulder is going to be there
if there is no breakout if there is no
base formation then there are chances
that this will not become a reverse head
and shoulder pattern
a reverse head and shoulder pattern will
be confirmed only if right shoulder is
confirmed and right shoulder will be
confirmed only when there is a
consolidation and there is a breakout
with green candle
on closing basis
a lot of people teach us that we should
buy only when it is breaking out above
the neckline
right
a lot of people are teaching us
to buy only when it is giving a breakout
here above the neckline
but I am saying when we are trading in
v40 and v40 next companies we don't need
to wait
up to the breakout above the neckline we
can buy when there is a base formation
and there is a breakout with green
candle
here itself
right so to make a base it's a very uh
artistic approach
that there should be a base
this is a base we can see all these
candles are trading in a Range
and this candle is above the range
with green candle on closing basis so
this is the buying point
right this is the buying point we will
be buying either at the end of the day
if we are available or next day in the
morning
so buying can be done either on the same
day if we are having a look at the chart
at 3 15 or 320 or 325 but better is to
buy next day in the morning
because uh almost all of us are working
somewhere either in corporate or we are
Homemaker or uh we are having a own
business so we might not be finding time
to uh analyze these stocks during the
market hours
so after coming home if we analyzed so
next day in the morning we can buy
so for example if we had bought it here
then technical Target Let's uh measure
it once again
from the bottom of the head till the
neckline
and we are plotting it above the
right
a technical Target is 23.29
so from this buying point if we are
buying just after the
right shoulder first right shoulder
our potential gain is 58 percent however
if we are buying it above the neckline
our potential gain is
40 so there is a big difference between
58 and 40 percent
are you getting my point
and because there is no stop loss
if after giving a breakout price starts
coming down then someone who is buying
above the neckline will be in big lows
of course that is a temporary loss
because these are great companies
however the drawdown will be much more
larger
but if we are buying just after the
breakout from the right shoulder base
then our drawdown will be much lesser
than those are buying above the neckline
and the confirmation is here uh once
stock make a base on the right shoulder
and give a breakout on console on
closing basis with a green candle this
is Almost sure that price is going to
hit the top
but of course
we need to understand that this is not
fixed deposit we cannot say that
maturity date is after one year or after
six months or after five years or two
years or three years this is stock
market
always remember two things are not in
our control
one the volatility and second the
holding period
these two things are not in our control
sometimes the stock price will keep on
trading in the same range for six months
and in next four months or five months
the target will be
achieved
there's a probability like that
and during these first six months when
the stock price is not doing anything
all other stocks might be going off
and we could be getting frustrated Vivek
Bhai my money is stuck in that stock it
is not doing anything whereas all other
stocks are going up
so again we need to note down one more
thing please note it down operators
don't have too much money that they can
trade all the stocks at the same time
operators don't have too much money
that they can operate all the stocks at
the same time they cannot
they have limited money
though they have a big money but still
that is a limited money
all the stocks cannot be operated at the
same time
so what they usually do
they start making their position
they keep on accumulating stocks below a
certain level
and after they achieve their target
means Target of accumulating a certain
number of stocks they start taking it on
the higher side
until that time they don't accumulate
the number of stocks they wanted
they will not take the stock price
higher they will wait
and this waiting period depends on the
people on the public those are holding
those stocks when the paces of these
retail public will be
broken
okay when the fear will be there in
their mind when the greed will come in
their mind okay my this stroke is the
battery stocks all other stocks are
going up okay I will sell this
when they will start exiting from the
stop because the holding period is too
long
during this accumulation
these operators
could be accumulating these stocks
within three months it could take six
months it could take sometimes two years
as well and that's why the width of the
reverse head and shoulder pattern is
varying all the time
in few cases the width is only three
months few cases this is 10 months in
few cases this is one year two years as
well for example last year I had made a
video on Mirza International
the holding means the width of the
reverse head and shoulder pattern was
more than a year
so it depends
like if we open the chart Mirza
International
just have a look at it the holding
period
so what are the connecting points one
Connecting Point second Connecting Point
third Connecting Point
and four connecting points and fifth
Connecting Point
can you see this
so how is this this is the left one
shoulder this is the left second
shoulder and this big is the head
and this is the right first shoulder and
this is the right second shoulder
so holding period means this
accumulation time is
from 27th June 19 till 3rd November 2021
it's more than two years
right you got it it could be different
it depends on the people those are
holding it and operator wants to buy
from them
it depends on that
but once the target of these operators
to accumulate a certain number of shares
will be achieved they will start taking
it higher otherwise they they will wait
the people those will be waiting for the
right time in stock market will be
making money
whether this is to buy the stock or this
is the holding period to sell the stock
people those will be waiting for the
right time based on the technical
analysis means the buying point and
selling point those will have patience
to wait until then we'll be making money
these operators are so patient that they
can hold a stock for three four years
without making any money
and later on they will start taking it
higher in next two years all Targets
will be achieved
so it's like a state run roadways buses
if a bus is late
then the driver will try to speed up to
reach on the time
right
it's like that now I am taking the same
example of Reliance Industries once
again
so this target was achieved now in this
particular case the
making of This reverse head and shoulder
pattern period was only six months only
six months so it will always be varying
always
while
having this neckline the vertical the
horizontal line
we can ignore
these Wicks Wicks going up or red candle
crossing the red candles
however the body of a green candle
should not be crossed
like this
are you getting a point because we are
having a horizontal line
so there could be some cases that all
connecting points are not exactly at the
same level means 345 345 345 345
because this is not a drawing
with a geometry box this is the real
Trading
there could be first Connecting Point is
345 second Connecting Point could be
347. third Connecting Point could be 3
55 however however the body of a green
candle should not be crossed while
drawing this connecting line
please note it down the body of a green
candle should not be crossed
while drawing the neckline the
horizontal line body of the green candle
should not be crossed
we will see some example to understand
this
the body of the green candle
should not be crossed however while
drawing this neckline the horizontal
line the wick of the candle could be
crossed and the body of red candle could
be crossed
there could be a question in our mind
that Vivek Bhai most of the reverse head
and shoulder pattern were made during
covet time
that this reverse reverse head and
shoulder pattern was created because of
the Corvette impact we don't need to
analyze the reason of this fall when
there is a reverse head and shoulder
pattern in these v40 and v14 next
companies
or every
every all these companies for all will
be supported or justified by a reason
so operators will make a use of these
reasons to bring the prices down
and when the
reverse head and shoulder pattern was
created during covet time it's not like
that after that none of the reverse side
and shoulder pattern has been created
there are reverse Head and Shoulder
patterns those are being created now as
well
and now the reason could be given that
this is because of the Russia Ukraine
war that's okay any of the reason could
be there we don't care
of course we need the reason to bring
the prices down to make the head a
deeper one
there is no reason there is no fall we
need the reasons but we don't need to
justify the reason whether this is a
valid reason or not whether this means
the fall with this reason will work or
not we don't need to justify we don't
need to analyze
right
if there is a reason that is valid if
there is no reason the price could be
coming down without any reason as well
because of the overall fall in the
market
or without any reason we don't need to
find out a reason of the Fall
when stock price is making
reverse head and shoulder pattern
whether this is the shoulder whether
this is the head or the right shoulder
we don't need to find the reason
if there is a reason go if there is no
reason then also good it doesn't make
any difference
we need to understand the operator is
making this shape
operator is making this shape no one
else
no one has the capability to stop a
price at the same level again and again
other than operator
no one has so much of quantity to sell
at the same price again and again at the
same level
it could be done only by The Operators
and there is a specific motive behind
this
a specific motive behind this
right
I will tell you the motive
so uh the target was achieved within a
short period of time
the target was achieved within a short
period of time in 105 days 58 and the
same chart
when this Reliance Industries was making
reverse head and shoulder pattern and it
had not achieved the target I had posted
this chart on Twitter as well in the
month of June 2020
so it's not like that uh now today I
have found a chart pattern where the
reverse head and shoulder pattern was
there and it had achieved the target I
picked up that particular chart pattern
and I'm showing it to you no it's not
like that on the real time basis if you
will go on my Twitter timeline you will
find in the month of June 2020 I had
posted the same chart
right
so this is on Real Time basis for
example
one more chart pattern have else
there is a reverse head and shoulder
pattern
so this is the example
this is the example like
this is Connecting Point one
this is Connecting Point 2 and this is
Connecting Point three
here this week
is closed we ignore while drawing this
neckline we ignore this wake we ignore
this red candle
we need to adjust a little bit right
but we cannot ignore a green candle
the body of a green candle we cannot
ignore
you're getting this point
now
here we are taking the measurement
from the lower level of the head
till the neckline
and we will be plotting it on the upside
so the target is 684.
and the target was achieved very soon
however
wherever
the technical Target is lower than
lifetime High
in case of reverse head and shoulder
pattern if the technical Target is lower
than lifetime high in that case
our Target will be lifetime High itself
not the technical Target
please note it down
when the technical Target is lower than
lifetime High
in that case we will sell at the
lifetime High itself
not at the technical Target
however
if the technical Target is higher than
the lifetime High then we will sell at
the technical term
so there are two points one is the
technical Target and second is the
lifetime High
we will sell at the higher of these two
higher level of either of these two
means if the lifetime I is higher than
the technical Target we will sell at the
higher point that is the lifetime High
however if the technical Target is
higher than the lifetime High we will
sell at the technical Target that is The
Higher One
why that is so
because when operator is making reverse
head and shoulder pattern then he need
to accumulate a lot of shares
and he will be accumulating a huge
quantity only when he is bullish
at least a full lifetime high at least
up to Lifetime High otherwise he will
not buy such a big quantity
and that's why reverse head and shoulder
pattern is the most reliable chart
pattern in the world and ever working
every time it is working if the company
is good
I am repeating once again please note it
down in the
same word with the same word as a
definition if
the technical Target
is lower than
if the technical Target is lower than
lifetime High
lifetime High then we will sell at
when you will write it down exactly
in this with the same words and you will
read it again you will understand
if the technical Target is lower than
the lifetime High then we will sell at
the lifetime High
this is the first one and second if the
technical Target is higher than the
lifetime High please note it down also
not for you but for your kids
none of us none of us is required to
send our kids
to any corporate to become a employee
forever
we will be talking about it in the last
session we will be talking about
so uh second point I was telling if the
technical Target is higher than lifetime
High
then we will sell at technical Target
right
so in this case when we were analyzing
the chart of have else the technical
Target was
684 however the lifetime high was eight
zero five then we will not sell at the
technical Target we will sell at the
lifetime High
so in this case
if we see
this is the left shoulder
this is the head
and this is the right shoulder
and in this right shoulder
this is the base formation
during making the base formation we can
ignore the wicks
the states the intraday movement
you can note it down also please
while making a box while making a box
of Base formation
we can ignore
the wick w i c k Wick
or we can call it sticks as well the
sticks of the candles
the intraday movement
we can ignore
right
so in this particular case
there was the
breakout with green candle
foreign
here
and the technical Target was almost 21
percent however the lifetime High Target
was 42 percent
and we achieved this target
in 138 days
I had shared the same chart as well just
after few days
when I had shared the Reliance
Industries chart
I shared the same chart and said
in the same manner and I had traded in
both the stocks and I had made money
and everybody had questioned Vivek why
covet is not over how can you be so
bullish
I can be so bullish because operator is
I am trading with the operator
I have no other sense I have I have no
other idea I cannot talk to the
management
and management has no control over the
price action these are the operators
only
these are the operators only
so uh for example in the past as well
there was this chart pattern
right
this was cup with handle pattern we will
talk it later
reverse head and shoulder pattern if we
can find one no
let's see if we could see one here
exactly
so this is the one
this is the left shoulder
this is the head
this is one small shoulder there's one
more shoulder and there's one more
shoulder
so on the left hand side there's only
one shoulder
there is a head
there is solder one a smaller one there
is shoulder two
and this shoulder three
we will be buying
at the base breakout from the first
shoulder itself
this is the base
and there's a breakout with this green
candle
with practice you will be able to doing
this
we will measure the target the lowest
level of the head
till the neckline
we will plot it above the neckline and
here's the target
while
having a look at this technical Target
we will always see the highest level as
well
so the higher of technical Target of the
lifetime High
we will be selling it at the higher of
either of these two the technical Target
of the lifetime act in this case the
technical Target is higher than the
lifetime high so we will sell it
technical Target
so this 24.82 percent was made
not 24.82 percent a little bit lesser
22.4 percent in 210 days means seven
months and there was no covet at the
time
so there could be any reason
there could be any reason
so how these technical chart patterns
like reverse side and shoulder pedals
are being building up being building up
means before that we will see uh two
more chart patterns as well like
godrej's uh consumer
there was a proper reverse head and
shoulder pattern
this was the left shoulder this was the
head
and this was the right shoulder
it gave a breakout but came down again
right
so where
we would have bought it
this is the base formation
and there is a green candle with
on closing basis outside the range this
one here
so this is the buying level
this is the buying price
what is the technical Target
technical Target is from the lowest
level of the head till the neckline
and we will be plotting this
above the neckline
so the technical Target is one zero nine
five and because the lifetime high is
lower than that this is 975
so we will be taking the lifetime High
not the lifetime why the technical
Target
you got it
so in this case
when we had bought at this level
the stock price was trading at the same
level
even after
172 days almost 6 months
can we see this
even after six months the stroke price
was trading at the same level
and I had made a video on this
and everybody was criticizing Vivek Bhai
at this time when all the stocks are
going up you recommended this stock on
YouTube and it is not doing anything our
money system
first point I am not recommending any
stock I am teaching
on YouTube I'm teaching I'm not
recommending anything
I am not saying that you should buy it
at this price I'm not saying
second point
I have told many times that we should
not invest more than five percent in one
stock almost uh in 100 videos I have
told this thing on YouTube that we
should not invest more than five percent
in one stock
and after buying a stock the stock can
be in the same range
for a long period of time
and even it could go down first before
taking the up move
so here also while I am teaching you in
a closed room
as a personal students
I'm reminding once again there are four
things those are in our control
number one to find a good business that
has a growth Prospect in future
second to find a leading company in that
business that is having a good Financial
right and third
on the basis of technical analysis to
find a buying price
and fourth on the basis of technical
analysis itself to find the selling
price these four things are in our
control
but two things are not in our control
means the volatility of movement and
downside movement after buying and the
holding period these two things are not
in our control
and none of the successful Trader ever
tried
to control these two things
none of the successful Trader ever tried
because he himself knows about it that
these two things cannot be controlled
right so here in this chart itself when
sixth month had happened everybody was
saying Vivek Bhai this stock has not
done anything in six months how can we
expect that it will be doing something
dramatic in coming months but it did
so first six months it didn't do
anything but in another
another just three and a half months
it went up by 53 percent
so total time period it took
total time period it took was 284 days
first 180 days it did nothing and in
another 100 days it achieved 53 Target
so it will almost always happen like
this this is stock market operators will
not be going
with our advice we need to wait with the
operators
right we need to wait with the operators
operator himself is also waiting
right he himself is also waiting
so when the driver is waiting and driver
is also in hurry to reach at the
destination the passenger should be
patient
are you getting a point
in the same way
so if we go to the YouTube
we can find
go there is consumer
and Vivek single
this search is easy actually
there is go there is consumer yeah
so this video was made almost
when the price was 686
and Technical Target was just like this
even there was no breakout
can you see this this is a November 15
and on November 15 2020
this was the price
there was no breakout but my experience
was saying when this right shoulder is
having such a long base
such a long tight consolidation it will
break out on the upside only
you're getting my point
and we need to be patient and I made 58
in that stock
but a lot of us after waiting for five
months just exited at the same price and
in another four months it gave 53
percent
so we need to be patient I'm emphasizing
on this thing just because we are humans
we could be losing the patience
but this is stock market is a business
of having patience after doing four
things finding the right business
selecting the right company selecting
the Buy price and having the target we
need to be patient after doing four
exercise ourselves
we need to be patient
right and that's why because we don't
know which stock will be moving faster
and which stock will be moving slower
that's why we don't need to invest more
than three percent in money stock
that's why
right
one another example like this is
Oracle Financial Services ofss
there was the same chart pattern
just like this
there was a same chart pattern this is
the left shoulder this is the right
shoulder means the second left shoulder
this is the head
this is one shoulder this is another
shoulder and this is another shoulder
there's a breakout then
however
we will be buying
at the breakout with green candle on
closing basis from the first shoulder
itself so this is the range
so this is a breakout from this range on
closing basis however these are red
candles we will be waiting for the green
candle and green candle is here
so you got the importance of having a
green candle
there should be a breakout on closing
basis but with the green candle
because red candles
are weak candles
and intraday movement break out with
intraday movement means with the sticks
is not a strong breakout we need to see
the stock price to close above the range
with a green candle
right
so in this case
we need to measure the technical Target
technical Target from the lowest level
of the bottom
till the neckline and we need to plot it
above the neckline
and the technical Target is
4937 Simon simultaneously we need to see
the lifetime high price as well
and the higher of these two will be the
technical Target actual Target where we
will be selling so in this case when
technical Target is higher than the
lifetime High we will sell at the
technical Target itself
means that here
right
now this stock also did the same thing
so from the buying level
how much is the potential gain
this is
60.69 percent
but
after buying
after buying this stock was trading at
the same level even after seven months
214 days
right 214 days the stock price was
moving in the same range and everybody
was behind me
because I had uploaded this video as
well based on the same technical chart
pattern analyzing the same thing exactly
in the same manner
but on YouTube I cannot code means I
cannot guess the caller and say ah you
need to sell only at the Target it's
your wish because I cannot recommend
I can only teach that these technical
chart patterns will always hit the
target if the company is a good company
if the business is a good business
right
so it did nothing for seven months
but after
just after seven months it hit the
target in another
six months so total holding period was
it was not a long time to make sixty
percent gain
it was just 13 months
less than 13 months one year 25 days 60
gain and this stock did nothing in first
215 days seven months
and the same in the same manner I had
uploaded this video as well ofss
Vivek single
one year back if you are looking to
start an online business then
in the same manner see
this was the same technical Charter
there was no difference
so we need to be patient and these are
the live examples means uh
I'm not someone who would be uh picking
a few uh good stocks and uh after doing
the back testing I'll be showing it to
you no it's not like that
I'm posting these charts in public
domain on real-time basis
and I'm taking trades myself also and
I'm waiting for seven months myself also
as for example I am waiting
in pnb for last one and half year almost
now
my average price is 37 rupees
and I am holding it for last 18 months I
am buying more and more and more and I'm
waiting for my price that is the book
value 90 rupees
so even if my 37 rupees will become 90
rupees and it will take two years I will
be making huge money
but first one and a half year has no has
done nothing
but this means and there is no guarantee
that in next six months everything will
happen
so sometimes it may take more time and
sometimes the target may be hitting in a
less time
on an average on an average reverse head
and shoulder pattern is taking one year
sometimes six months sometimes one and
half a year
right
and there are a lot of stocks those are
making reverse head and shoulder pattern
now as well
for example
like access bank
this is a proper beautiful reverse head
and shoulder pattern
this is the left shoulder
this is the head
and this is the right short
and see what happened
there is a base
a small base and there's a Breakout
and I'm in gain
right
the technical Target is one zero zero
nine and lifetime high is not at that
level so our Target will be lifetime
High itself
and how much is the potential gain from
the buying level
this is 35 percent
right
and I had made this video as well
recently
axis Bank versus codec Bank four months
back access bank Heroes zero ten months
back
just wait
so this was trading at 6 57 then and now
it is trading at 903
it's almost going to be one year these
are 11 months and in 11 months from 6 57
what was the level of 657
November
last year
30th November
this was the exact bottom of that time
now we are making 38 percent
now a lot of people could be saying
Vivek Bhai this stock has done nothing
this stock has done nothing from here to
here
ah technical Target uh time period is
let me measure
from here to here the same level 220
days
but after this
I am almost making 40 percent
in another three and a half months
and in another video
this one
with the technical chart
see why I had made this video
and see the technical targets
can you see this 660 was the price
660 was the price
on 11th June this year itself
11th June
it was almost here
again the bottom
again the same bottom
so uh again just to repeat just to make
sure that you understand the importance
of this thing we have control only on
four things
and we don't have control on two things
the volatility and the holding period
sometimes we ourselves would be
criticizing ourselves only
that is there something wrong in my
understanding what Vivek bhaya taught
there's nothing wrong this is time
period the holding time could be
different for anyone
we need to be patient
we just need to be patient
are getting a point
reverse head and shoulder pattern is
such a simple chart pattern and always
working
but only in good companies
because based on the business and based
on the financials
we know that finally the stock prices
will be hitting lifetime High
when this is a good business and this is
a good company in that business posting
highest ever profits or has a consistent
track record of posting good numbers
then definitely the stock price will be
hitting lifetime high once again
right
so
how these Char patterns are being
built up
operators are using
operators are using stop loss
in creating these chart patterns
stop loss is the key
stop loss is the key by using that
operators are creating these shapes
reverse head and shoulder pattern
how
let's take the first example of Reliance
Industries
here in this case we all know that we
are using stop loss
in two methods one percentage wise and
second support wise
so few people are placing the stop loss
just below the support if the support is
broken
people are using the stop loss to exit
from the stock or if the stock price is
coming down by more than a specific
percentage like four percent or five
percent people are exiting from that
stock because uh uh usually retailers
are not willing to take more than 10
percent loss in one stock or eight
percent loss in one issue over five
percent loss in vanish
right and this is what is taught in the
market that we should always apply stop
loss
by the way who are teaching us
who are giving us a stop loss
in 99 cases
advisory firms are giving us
trading calls
in 99 cases like axis Bank issued this
report
codex security is issued this report
icsc securities issued this report HDFC
Securities report issued this report
like these advisory calls the stock
analysis reports
like
and every time they are giving three
points the buying point the Target and
the stop loss
so if they have analyzed a stock and it
is supposed to go up then why should I
sell if the stock price is down by five
percent or six percent or ten percent
this is much more cheaper now
if a stock price is trading at 100
rupees and the stock price came down to
90 rupees has the business started doing
something bad just because the stock
price has come down no
these are the same quarterly results
and there's no quarterly results in
between
so why the company is a bad company just
because the stock prices come down
and why should I exit with a eight
percent loss even I should buy more
if the company is good and if the
company is dicey if the company is not
good if the company is bad why you are
giving a recommendation to buy that
stock
just because there is a technical chart
pattern no that should not be the only
criteria
are you getting my point so why people
are using stop loss because they are not
sure about the business
because they are not sure about the
company
they are playing only technically
and that is the wrong approach
anyone who has used just technicals in
stock trading has never made billions
forget billions has never made Millions
and if someone has made millions they
have not been able to retain that
right this is a guy Mark Minar winning
a lot of us might have heard about him
Mark Minar winning
he's a technical analyst technical
Trader Equity Trader itself and he is a
world champion many times
he is a world champion many times
there's a uh competition in U.S where
world champion
are being selected means there is a
competition and people are winning in
that that uh who has made most
percentage gain within 365 days
so Mark minor Winnie has made
most of most money than anyone else
within a specific period of time and he
has won World Championship many times I
am showing it to you
mark minawini
he's the guy and he has written many
books I have read all these books
played like a stock market wizard trade
and Think Like A Champion momentum
Masters and mindset for winning
right
and he is a world champion
he takes a lot of seminars
you will read a lot about him right now
if we go back and we see the network of
this guy
how much is that Mark minarvini
estimated net worth is 30 million dollar
that's it
and this is August 2022 the latest
number
as of March 2022 his network has been
estimated at more than 30 million
dollars
between 25 to 13 million dollars
30 million dollar is 240 crore rupees
and he is considered one of the best
traders in the world
which is 240 crore rupees
and he has read more than 2 000 books on
his stock market
and his name was published in Market
wizard
the book authored by
Jackie Swagger
right
so why he is unable to retain that money
he has made a lot of money but why he
has been unable to retain that money
just because of simple thing he is using
his stop loss
so when the market is in a bull run he's
making money
but when Market is in a downside or
Market is in a consolidation mode he is
losing all the money
so what we need to do if the market is
in the upside we need to make money but
when the market is in a downside or
Market is in the same range we just need
to protect that money that's it
we cannot make money every month
we can if we are a full-time Trader
but when we are not a full-time Trader
we cannot make money every month
sometimes there will be a year time when
we won't be able to make any money
there could be time
but next year itself we will make double
of the money
so the average cagr will be more than 30
35 even 40 even more than 40 percent
in my offline course that I had uh in
the month of October last month in
gurgaon there are only 30 participants
in that offline course and that is only
for the people those have taken online
classes and those are willing to become
full-time Trader that course is only for
those people so uh there was one student
who had taken a class in my batch three
means almost two years back now
he had converted his five and half half
lakh rupees into 21 lakh rupees in just
two years
he was and he had just traded only on
Knoxville that's it
if there was no indicator based on
Knoxville he was not trading he was
keeping his money
with him in cash
and when there was a signal he was just
using that
just one is Taxi
why I'm telling you this
the simple reason I am teaching you
almost eight strategies I'll be I'll be
teaching you almost eight stats is seven
or eight
but we don't need to use all these
strategies together
we just need to find one or two we are
most comfortable with
right it depends that with which
strategy we are most comfortable with
if we are comfortable only in the large
cap only in the large care
then we need to trade with the
strategies which is applicable only on
v40 companies
right we don't need to go outside v40
but if we are okay to trade in all the
group of companies then we need to trade
on the basis of v20
because v20 is applicable on v40 v14
next and v21
so it depends we will be talking about
it in the last session that how to move
forward now after teaching average tax
after teaching after learning everything
not after teaching after learning
average students
right
so uh when we are talking about
this uh stop loss
so usually when the stock price is
trading in this range
when the stock price moved up
up to this level and it started coming
back from this price let me just do one
thing remove all the drawing and teach
you now
so the last
resistance was this
and when the time is here
so the support is this
so this is the resistance right
and this is the support
and when the stock price hit the same
resistance what people will be thinking
that it might not be giving a breakout
Above This resistance
and if someone has bought it here and
the price started coming down
and this is below the buying price what
everybody will be doing they will be
placing the stop loss at the last
support
usually
and what operator did
Operator just push the price lower than
this level lower than this support
people sold off their stocks because
there was a stop loss at this level
and Operator just operator was buying
only below this level
and operator did
means they just
bring the prices up again in the same
range but hitting the same resistance
again
people were thinking about oh no this is
the third time this resistance there was
no breakout from this resistance
again
now the support is this
people will be putting the stop loss
below the support means below this thing
every time whenever there will be a
breakdown below the support below the
stop loss
the chart pattern will be made
here operator you started buying again
and Retail public was selling
then there was a stop loss here
operator played again whose the price is
lower to buy it at the lower level
Again The price came up but it was
hitting the same resistance
so why it was hitting the same
resistance and why the prices was coming
down because
operator could not buy a certain number
of shares he wanted to buy that's why at
the same level he was selling his own
shares few shares to bring the prices
down
so that people can think that this is a
strong resistance
and general public could start selling
and he was just bringing the price below
the support so that people could sell
after hitting his stop loss
so the moment when retailers are hitting
the stop loss and they are selling
operators are buying
whenever a support is broken whenever a
support is broken general public do sell
and operators Dubai
always
this fall is in our favor
this poll is required in the market to
make a technical setup to make a
technical chart pattern
this breakdown below the support is the
indication that operators are existing
there
operators are buying there
operators do never buy at a higher level
operators always buy where there's a
hitting of stop loss by the retail
public
always they are the smart people
operators are the people having the
deepest pocket having the largest money
having the best Nexus of bureaucrats
diplomats ministers
they have a Lobby they have a
intelligent people I'm saying
intelligent people IIT pass out I am
pass out
working for them
making algorithms
understanding the retailers
way of working
right they have influence they can
publish any news anytime in any media
they can Flash anything
so that there is a panic in the market
and the support is breaking down and
Retail public is hitting the stop loss
and they are buying
otherwise what is the reason
that Colgate Palmolive stock price is
coming down below it per day below a
certain support what is the reason
means who will stop using Colgate
what will be the reason that Colgate
will be posting less net profit there is
no reason
there is no reason this is the only
product that is being used
by everyone and the number of people
will be using it more
how we wake by when everybody is using
it now itself
why people will be using more we need to
become a common man to understand this
for example
how many people how many people in rural
area those are about 70 years old having
all the teeth
very less people
and they don't have money to have
artificial teeth
they don't have money
and with having fewer teeth can they buy
toothbrush of Colgate
can can they use toothpaste
no they are not doing anything
they are not doing anything
but when these old people will be going
from this earth when they will be
completing their age
of course when in India if one crore
people are dying one crore people are
taking birth as well
and all the kids will be having teeth
and all these all people means the
grandpas and grandmothers
they were not having teeth
so one crow people those were not using
Colgate are going having no impact on
Colgate and one more new people are
coming those will be using Colgate
so when everybody is thinking that
Colgate is being used by everyone and
the uses will not be increased this is
wrong uses will be increased
we need to become a common man
and to understand this do we need to
have a certificate from IIT or IIM
or do I need to pass out from London
Business School or from NCR
no
I need to understand business I need to
become a baniya
right
not from the cast from the thinking
we need to see the opportunity
and this is so simple
right
the toothbrush we are using is costing
only 20 20 rupees 25 rupees or 30 rupees
right having the same manufacturing cost
but the same toothbrush which is being
solved for kids is costing 99 rupees or
199 rupees where the manufacturing cost
is same
but the design is different and we are
buying
right and with the more purchasing power
with the more purchasing power because
we are getting richer every year with
the growth rate with the GDP growth
more people are buying 200 rupees
toothpick toothbrush for their kids
so we need to understand why Colgate is
growing and why Colgate will keep on
growing
it's so simple
we don't need to go outside v40
companies to make money
again I'm saying
we just need to keep on trading in v40
companies and we will be so secure we
will be feeling so secure that our money
is invested in such a great company that
India's life is miserable without these
products
right
we just need to be patient that's
we need to understand the business
that's it
so question comes Vivek by why you are
applying these reverse head and shoulder
pattern in a lot of stocks those are not
the part of b40 or v40 next
today
So my answer is the right to do is
turned is mine it's not yours
right
with practice you will also be able to
do instance
but not now
and one more thing
I am on a public platform now
I need to analyze a lot of stocks
because a lot of people might be having
these stocks
and while applying this reverse head and
shoulder pattern I am making sure that
the company is a good company from that
point of view
even though that is not a part of v40
but that is a good company from business
point of view and from Financial point
of view as well I'm making sure
because my credibility
is only stake whenever I am uploading
any video
right so but how because we are here to
make money only in our own account and
our Target is to uh our wish is to have
100 crore rupees worth of portfolio
then we don't need to trade in a lot of
companies however I'll be uh telling you
the exact way out in the sixth session
that how to move on
which states the which company group and
how many strategies how many groups we
will be learning that
right
uh we'll be taking a very short break
this is 9 38 we'll be meeting at 9 45
and we will learn rest to strategies
right
9 45
to start going
please come
yes
so the second strategy
that is again
which I have already discussed many
times on YouTube that is the cup with
handle pattern
but we need to apply all these
strategies with rules so that we can get
good results
right
cup with handle pattern
yes
the last strategy can be average
I'll be teaching uh in the third
strategy that how to average because
that is the another strategy uh and uh
we will be averaging uh in that yeah
so uh
next one is the cup with handle pattern
and the complete handle pattern is also
applicable on v40 and v40 next
cuff with handle pattern strategy is
also applicable on v40 and v40 next
we will be investing three percent of
the portfolio in that stock
and
noise stop loss
again
this strategy is very similar to reverse
head and shoulder pattern with a very
few differences
for example
this is
reverse head and shoulder pattern
right
but if there is no left shoulder
then it will become the cup with handle
pattern
right so if
this is the
cuff with handle pattern
and we
Mark left shoulder as well
then it will become reverse side and
shoulder pattern
so a reverse head and shoulder pattern
without left shoulder is cuffed with
handle better
so we can note it down exactly in the
same way
Rakesh Bhai you are late a bit
so our next strategy name is
cup with handle pattern
I'm repeating once again cup with handle
pattern
we will be using this strategy on v40
and v40 next companies
and three percent of the total portfolio
will be invested
in one stock based on this
and cup with handle pattern means
reverse head and shoulder pattern
without left shoulder
right without left shoulder it will
become cuff with handle pattern
so as uh we had discussed v40 and v40
next we will be applying this on v40 and
v40 next and reverse head and shoulder
pattern also on v14 and v40 next
right so so far uh this is the fifth
strategy first one was moving average
that was only on v40 Knoxville only on
v40 and then v20 that was on v40 v40
next and v200 reverse head and shoulder
pattern v14 in v40 next and cup with
handle v40 and v40 next
okay no stop loss
and one thing one difference is uh as in
case of reverse head and shoulder
pattern while marking the technical
Target we were
raising this target up to the lifetime
high if the lifetime high is higher than
the technical Target however in case of
cup with handle pattern the technical
Target is the selling Target
we will not be raising the technical
Target up to Lifetime High we will not
raise
we will keep the technical Target as the
final selling Target
this is clear
as we had discussed that the shape of
shoulders
could not be in the same proportion as
the head or the shape of two shoulders
right and left one could be different
with the difference in width and depth
and there could be more solders on
either side in the same manner there is
no uh proportion or there is a uh no
symmetry in cup and handle the shape of
the cup could be you it could be V it
could be tough pattern
right
it could be any shape
right and
in the same manner there could be more
than one handle
please note it down there could be more
and if there are more handle than one
then we will call it complex cup with
handle pattern
and complex cuff with handle patterns
are more reliable than normal cup with
handle pattern always because operator
is taking more time
operator is bringing the prices once
again to buy few more quantities
that's why
so one more handle means operator wants
to buy more
and when operator is buying more this is
what we want
someone who can take the prices higher
is buying more
yes of course the handle
should have less depth than the cup cup
is like the head
it should be much more deeper
right
so the cup should be bigger than the
handle
this is the cup and this could be handle
however it could not be like that this
is the cup
and this is the handle no this is not
the handle handle can never be bigger
than the cup
the handle can never be bigger than the
cup
so sometimes there could be shape like
like this means a
this one
and this one
so this is the
connecting line however
neither this is reversed and shoulder
pattern no this is cuff with handle
pattern
right
why the simple reason
this is not a valid cup with handle
pattern because the handle cannot be
bigger than the cup
and this is not a reverse head and
shoulder pattern because to make a right
shoulder it should have come down from
here itself without giving a breakout to
make a right shoulder
and this right shoulder should be lower
than the head
got it
so sometimes there could be pattern
where there is no handle or there is no
right shoulder
so those are not the right chart pattern
to trade
we will have to trade only when there is
a right handle or there is the right
shoulder
okay
so here the buying point will be exactly
like the buying point in Reverse head
and shoulder pattern
here we will find a base formation at
the right handle and right handle means
the first handle there could be more
than one handle
so at the
first handle itself we will see the base
formation
we will see the Breakout we will see the
breakout with green candle and we will
see the breakout from base formation
with green candle on closing bases
right
so for example
Aris life science is one of the finest
Pharma company and not a big company
but not a smaller one as well so if we
see what is the
market capitalization of Aries life
science this is 10 000 crore almost
and this is meeting all our conditions
that this is the part of v40 next
right
so in Aries life science
there is a cup with handle pattern
like this
so here if you see we are ignoring a lot
of weights
but only waves
no green candle body only works
here
this is the cup
this is the handle
and this is one more handle
and this is one more handle a lot of
handle so this is a complex cup with
handle pattern
right this is clear this is complex cup
with handle pattern and because
at the first handle itself because we
don't know whether one more handle will
be made or not we need to buy at the
first handle itself
so if we see where is the base formation
can we call these three candles as the
base formation yes we can call but if we
have a doubt whether in such a big shape
these three kind of could make a base
we don't need to be in a doubt we can
consider this one as a
base formation a range
trading in a Range
so there could be sometimes a doubt
between whether these three candles is a
proper base or not can we take this
larger base to consider a breakout from
we should always
give the benefit
to make ourselves much more sure there
is no need of any type of hurry we
should not be in a hurry to take a trade
where we are much more confident we
should take a trade only
okay
so we are considering this larger base
as the base and the breakout with the
green candle is here
so
our buying point is this
right our buying point is this so now if
we see after buying
the stock was trading almost in the same
range for quite a long time and it was
not up after even after four months it
was available at almost the same price
however we bought it here
and we are measuring the target
the depth of the cup
up to neckline
and we are placing this depth
above the neckline
to have the selling Target
and Target is
almost 800 799
the target is almost same
now we must have bought it here
it did nothing for four months almost
but it achieved the target
and total Target was
from the buying level is 70 percent in
the exact 365 days
right
so if someone had bought above the
neckline he must not have made too much
of money so much of money
and
from 4th May 21
till the target was achieved 36 percent
was made in just three months
and in the first nine months how much
money was made from the buying level
only 27.47 percent in nine months
SO waiting is utmost important
otherwise
you understand what I mean to say
we will not be making money otherwise so
simple
and we will be getting frustrated I
don't want that's why I'm emphasizing on
this point again and again because this
is the key to success in stock trading
after buying we need to forget the stock
until it achieve the target
and if we think that we have much more
opportunities based on the Learned
strategies and we are okay to have much
more stocks then this is okay to invest
two percent in one stock and have 50
trades this is okay from my side
if we can work out and we can find more
means we can spend more time on
technical analysis and finding right
chart patterns and finding right buying
opportunities it's okay to have two
percent in one trade and have 50 trades
this is okay absolutely fine there is
nothing wrong but we should not take
we should not invest more than three
percent in one stock at a time
all right
so
the cup with handle pattern is much more
easier there is
means this is almost similar to uh
reverse head and shoulder pattern but
one major difference is there when
operator is uh
making this shape in cup with handle
pattern he is not hitting the stop loss
of retailers
because there is no breakdown below the
support
right there is no left handle there is
no left shoulder
and support is being broken only when
the price is coming below the left
shoulders
right you need to watch the videos again
you need to revise the sessions
two three times and if you could revise
five times this is good we need to uh
keep all these information in our
subconscious mind right now your active
mind means your conscious mind is
grasping this information but again and
again when we will be revising these
sessions this will become the part of
our habits
means it will be stored in our inner
memory
we need to do this for example
I have read the secret book almost 43 44
times
the secret almost 43 44 times
one up on Wall Street I have read almost
13 times the best book on investing ever
written
written by Peter Lynch one up on Wall
Street
foreign
of that book
this one
and this is available in Hindi as well
as in English
the best book I'm saying the best book
right
so the second strategy is uh over now
today's second strategy handle is very
easy very simple there are two major
differences one that the technical
Target is the actual Target
right and what is the second difference
there's no second difference
what is the second difference please you
can unmute and tell me so there is no
left shoulder
operator cannot hit stop loss exactly
operator is not hitting the stops that
is the second difference
means we must need to understand the
psychology behind the chart pattern
and then only we will have conviction to
trade based on that
we must need to have a we must need to
understand the psychology why these
chart patterns are being built up by The
Operators and how
because this is not a drawing yes please
be required
can you please repeat this operator is
not hitting the stop loss
in this way see uh are being hit when
the price is coming down below the last
support
so in this cup with handle pattern last
support was this and the price didn't
came down below this and the next
support was this price didn't came down
below this the next support was this
price didn't came down so operator was
not hitting the stop loss of retailers
it was just bringing the price down from
this resistance level so that people
could be in panic
and they can sell off and they can means
operator can buy
but
operator understand here if he would be
hitting
they stop loss by bringing the price
below the support line
might be he will be losing the control
sometimes or he might not be having so
much of money that the flood of shares
those will be in the market he could buy
all of them
okay
so there could be any reason
right now the third strategy we are
going to learn is one of the best so far
and that will be making the fastest
money
and this is V10 strategy we have learned
v20 in the last sessions now this is V10
this is the third strategy today we are
going to learn
here can I ask you one question yes
please
ah so the previous chart that we were
looking at right uh so the cops with
handle pattern there is life sense is
one so in that I just wanted to ask you
for my understanding the
um after the you know Target was hit I
was seeing that there was another cup
with handle pattern that was getting
formed so just wanted to check is that a
correct assumption
over here
right after the Target that was hit this
one this is small one correct and the
right shoulder
yes exactly this was the
correct so this would also be considered
as another couple
um
right it can also be considered but but
as I told you that we each to try to
find out a uh pattern where the
potential gain is almost 40 percent
oh right sorry yeah okay yeah so so this
is the thumb rule this is not a thumb
rule but this will give us a cushion to
find a trade where operator wants a big
Target
indeed right
we should
always avoid and and we can make a rule
as well we can make a rule as well
please note it down
that if there is a chart pattern on the
lifetime High
if there is a chart pattern being built
up at the lifetime High because this was
this was on the lifetime High the
connecting points was on the lifetime
High okay second is small cup with
handle pattern the connecting points
were on the lifetime high so if the
connecting points are on the lifetime
high in case of reverse side and
shoulder pattern and cuff with handle
pattern the minimum potential gain
should be 40 percent
so we can make this one thumb rule
right so this is another rule
we can make here
if the connecting points in case of rhs
and cwh is at the lifetime High then
potential gain should be minimum 40
percent
right now the V10 we are moving to the
V10
V10 strategy is based on
cup with handle pattern and reverse head
and shoulder pattern
V10 strategy you can note it down
V10 strategy is based on rhs and cwh
rhs and CWS this is based on that so
indirectly V10 is also applicable only
on v40 and v40 next
indirectly V10 is also applicable on
v40 and v40 next because this is based
on rhs and cwh cwh is the cup with
handle rhs means reverse Head and
Shoulder pack
calling cwh is much more easier actually
cup with handle reverse head and
shoulder pattern is a long sentence
now this V10 will be applicable during a
specific period only
please note it down these are few uh
points if we will note it down then we
can teach these strategies to our kids
in a proper manner
and we need to do that
those who have the younger ones don't
have kids
they have much more time don't no no
need to worry you have much more time
you can enjoy your life
so uh
V10 is applicable in a specific period
and that period is
from the beginning of buying please note
it down exactly in the same way
so that when you will read you will
understand
it is applicable
from the buying point
till till the selling point
this is applicable
between the buying point
and the selling point
based on
cup with handle and rhs
right
so for example
if we if we do take the same example
here
and we plot the
same neckline
and we measure the technical Target
right so where is the buying point
buying point was above this range
right and which is the selling point
selling point is this
right
so V10 will be applicable
between this period
before this we will not apply V10 and
after this we will not apply this V10
means before but
whether we have bought based on rhs or
cwh has nothing to do with this
I am talking about the applicability
right there could be a case when we have
not bought based on the rhs but we can
still take a trade based on V10
when buying has been signaled by the
chart pattern based on cup with handle
pattern so this is applicable in between
this period from the buying Point based
on technical chart pattern on rhs and
cwh
till the selling point during this
period
when a signal has come up based on
reverse side and shoulder pattern or
cuff with handle pattern VH V10 is
applicable
till what time this is applicable until
the target is achieved based on cwh and
rhs between this treatment
okay
between this period
so it means
first a stock need to qualify in rhs or
cwh
then only we can trade in V10
so there are two tests
there are two conditions
first the stock need to qualify on rhs
or cwh
and then second
it need to qualify based on wheat and
conditions
and once the target is achieved based on
reverse head and shoulder pattern or
coffee handle pattern
first condition will not any more
applicable so V10 will not be applicable
okay
now
we will be investing three percent of
the total portfolio in V10 again
and we can average also
So based on this technically there could
be three trades
suppose we have taken one trade based on
coffees handle pattern or reverse head
and shoulder pattern and second trade we
have taken based on V10
and we have taken one more trade based
on weekend so there could be three
trades in total
three percent plus three percent plus
three percent it means there could be
case that we are
investing total nine percent of the
portfolio in one stock but on different
different time different different
labels
one based on copy the handle pattern say
for example another trade we took based
on V10 and one more trade we we took
based on V10 so on the basis of v10 we
can take two trips I will teach you how
it
so in this case
once the buying is applicable based on
cup with handle pattern
any fall that is more than or equal to
10 percent from any level
after this applicability any fall that
is more than 10 percent
say for example
here is the fall of more than 10 percent
from any Peak from any high level once
the highest level is made any 10 fall
will be giving us a buying opportunity
based on Wheaton
So based on this red candle
this red candle it there was a fall of
ten percent more than 10 percent but at
the 10 percent itself we must have taken
the trade
so we must have taken this trade
based on vetan
and where we are selling it
once it is hitting the same upper line
from where it has retraced by 10 percent
this level
so it's a gain of 11 percent within a
short period of time that is eight days
only
foreign
this is clear this is easy
so once there is a buying signal based
on reverse head and shoulder pattern or
cup with handle pattern after the buying
signal there is a fall of ten percent
from any level
this is a retracement of 10 percent this
is a pullback of 10 percent
so all these are the same words
retracement pull back or fall
ten percent we will be buying
for the same level from where it had
started coming down
right so ten percent eleven percent is
made within eight days by doing this
again now after hitting this target we
have just one trade open
this one we had taken one trade here and
second trade here so this second trade
is over now
the target is achieved
and after achieving this target
it came Again by 10 percent
we bought it again
for the same Target
and now
it started moving up we can see
if this is down by 10 again
we need to understand if this is down by
10 again
and the again 10 percent
should be at there should be a gap of at
least five percent between the first
wheat and trade and second wheat and
trade please note it down
the second trade based on V10 should be
five percent lower than the first V10
trade
the second wheat and trade
should be at least five percent lower
than the first wheat and trade
of course there should be some Gap
otherwise there is no sense to average
once again
there should be some Gap
right so in this case
the another fall 10 percent and there is
a gap of 5 percent
the first V10 after minsa this return
was done
next video we had taken here there was
the up move and again a fall of ten
percent so second Wheaton is here but
second V10 should be lower by at least
five percent and we can see this is
lower by 5.28 percent almost
5.5
so second was taken here now
and all these traits will have
respective targets
so this third rate was
means the target was achieved here 25
days 11 gain and this upper one it took
some time but before
so you you need to understand one thing
I am just giving the numbers so first
trade we had taken based on reverse head
and sorry cup with handle pattern
second trade was here based on V10 the
target was achieved
and the third trade was taken on V10
which is open
and the fourth trade we have taken based
on V10
the target is achieved
and when this target is also achieved we
have two trades open now the first one
and the third one
first one based on cup with handle
pattern and third one based on V10 so
now on the basis of v10 only one trade
is open it means if one more opportunity
comes we can trade one more
we can take one more trade based on beta
you got it based on wheat and we can
have two trades at a time
right
so this fourth straight Target was
achieved here and immediately after that
we can see from this level there is a
fall of ten percent
right
however
again just to remind you
the gap between
existing open trade based on V10 and the
new trade that is coming based on wheat
and there should be a gap of at least
five percent
so this difference is only three percent
we can
bring it down up to five percent means
if the price come down up to here we can
take it
you got it
you need to revise the video again and
you will become habitual this is easy we
just need to see the steps
but once we will be
you know uh habitual uh to trade based
on this we will be making most of the
money in best of the companies
we will be taking every movement for our
benefit
we will be booking profit and we will be
taking trades we will be booking profit
and we will be taking trades
in this case we'll be making more than
11 percent because the target means the
buying price is lower now so this is the
fifth trade we are taking
this is the fifth grade we are taking
and the target was achieved
from this level up to this level and
this is 13.74 percent gain in just two
months
this target is achieved and once this
target is achieved we have one trade
open based on Wheaton that is the trade
number three and one trade open based on
cup with handle that is the trade number
one
now this third trade
the target is achieved for this third
trade as well and it took a little bit
more time
but not that long
it took almost four and a half months to
give us 11 percent gain
this target is also achieved now
we have taken four trades based on V10
and all Targets are achieved
right all Targets are achieved
now uh again we need to see if there is
a fall of ten percent
this is not 10 this is six and half
percent
I'm removing all these drawings where
the targets have been achieved
okay and this is a fall of ten percent
now here
yes this is the sixth trade we will be
taking
this is the sixth trade
we will take here
and
because there's a fall of ten percent
ten percent fall is here
the buying is here
and the target is achieved immediately
after that
39 days again 11 gain so this target is
also achieved again there is a fall of
ten percent we can see
this is the seventh trade we are taking
this is the seventh state we are taking
and the target is achieved
in 49 days
11 gain in 49 days
okay if there is a ten percent fall
again let's see
no and the final Target is also achieved
so during this period we took six trades
based on V10 and one trade based on cuff
with handle pad
we will keep on making money if we will
keep ourselves Within
v40 and v40 next
because when there is a v time we must
have money to invest
and this will be available when we'll be
trading only in a small group of
companies
we'll be talking about it in the last
session
but this V10
is a master stroke
this V10 is keeping us with the largest
and best companies and giving us amazing
money
the average holding period based on V10
is less than two months
right the average holding period based
on V10 is less than two months
and there are a lot of opportunities lot
of opportunity if if I give you one more
example like a Bajaj Finance
in Bajaj Finance if we see
there's a couple handle pattern
right
there is a proper cuff with handle
pattern
and there's a base formation as well
and there's a breakout as well
and let's see if the potential gain is
more or less 40 or not
from the buying point
so from the buying level
this is here with the green candle
Breakout
this is almost
34.84 percent so we can take a trade
this is almost 40 percent means this
this is not a 10 15 potential gain this
is 35 technical gain a potential gain we
can take the trade
so first trade we can take
because the price is trading below the
buying point now
so one trade can be taken based on cuff
with handle pattern this one
this trade can still be taken because
the current price is below the first
buying price
now currently and second let's see if
there is a V10 as well if this is down
by 10 percent or not
this was 10 down
day before yesterday means
the second last trading session
10 down
and what will be the target target will
be again from where it had started
coming down for 10 for
So currently we can take two trades
one based on coffee handle pattern on
second
based on the V10
so this V10 holding we will have
till here only
up to here
right and the first buying we will have
until the final Target is achieved based
on cup with handle pattern that is 9981
this is so simple
and there's no risk we are in Bajaj
finser Bajaj Finance
there's no risk
what we need to do
we just need to have a discipline
we just need to have a discipline we
always pray and ask means I always wish
he is
please please give me power
please give me courage to follow my own
strategies with discipline
money will follow money will come
automatically
these are well proven strategies
again the time period could be different
every time based on the market
situations
we don't have any control bit on the
holding period and the volatility we
don't have any control
but
as the nature do change from Summer to
Winters and Winters to Summer
the stock market prices also do change
from the uptrend to the downtrend and
downtrend to the uptrend the downtrend
could be much more longer sometimes and
uptrend also could be much more longer
sometimes but the basic nature of these
great companies is to move up only
that's why
whenever these stock prices are coming
down and we have a disciplined approach
we just need to go and take a trade we
don't need to have a look at the market
situations
because whenever the price will come
down it will be in most of the cases
coupled with the bad news
so our conscious mind could be telling
us no this is not the right time this
price is coming down because of this bad
news and it can go further down
we don't need to listen to the conscious
mind
we need to listen to the subconscious
and that's why I'm saying just revise
these sessions five times six times so
that it could become a habit to take a
trade when the conditions are being met
there is no second question when
conditions are being met there is no
question
all good stocks will come down because
of the bad news only
and the situation will change again
right
now is the time for
few questions those you might be having
we can start
you can unmute and ask
sir for the uh
yeah so the very beginners who are
starting from the day one okay best
books you will you recommend for
foundation for making foundation for
making Foundation I will say to go to
zerodha Varsity first
sir uh you will go to the uh versity
okay
foreign
yes
so this is uh zerothar.com Varsity right
okay this is the
URL and uh right sir I am just pasting
it on the chat box this is the URL
zerodha.com varsity varsity so this is
uh giving you uh all basic information
and I would recommend even if we have a
prior experience all of us should go
through this there could be few terms
few words few sentences few information
even though we are trading for last 10
years we might not be knowing
always remember one thing we don't know
what we don't know
right we don't know what we don't know
we just need to explore
right there could be a lot of things
those we might not be knowing
thanks
and second after this
one upon what basically there are three
books written by Peter Lynch
the first book Is Learn to Earn
the first book Is Learn to Earn and this
is the basic one
so these three books written by Peter
Lynch should be read in the same
sequence the first is Learn to Earn
right sir and second is one up on Wall
Street
right sir and third one is beating the
street beating
b-e-a-t-i-n-g beating the street means
outperforming
beating the street right third one
next question please thank you
so yes sir
this uh for the base formation uh
minimum how many candles we need to uh
it will depend on the size of
overall movement sometimes four or five
candles will be sufficient when the uh
downside movement is a small one and
sometimes means if there are four or
five candles then this is more than
sufficient okay thank you
yes please I was wondering if you can
bring together our group effort and uh
have a Interactive Group uh whereby one
can um uh uh kind of alert everybody if
at all they come across a pattern so
that will give real Synergy to our
group in terms of benefit see I can do
that I can do that however my experience
is if I'll if I will be doing this then
nobody will be able to make money
what is the reason you feel the reason
is
we have a habit to type
our thumbs have
means they are addicted to type anything
every time
and a lot of us will not be stopping
watching TV
so if something will be coming on TV
we'll be sending the URL on the WhatsApp
group
we have the bad habit then one has to
definitely cross check once we cannot
rely on the prompts only if we are
convinced of the alerts then one can
kind of take a call it a shot one more
one more thing
no one in this world has made 100 crore
rupees with someone else helped
you will get a bad habit
you will not be becoming independent
all Traders those have made 100 crore
are doing it independently
yeah I I got your point it's a valid
point but one you can try exploring what
I have suggested it's up to you I have
tried exploring this this is the 28th
batch okay
so uh there have been 27 batch earlier
and there was a mess oh charger oh there
was a mess
see if you want to have friendship with
few of us
of course you can have
there's nothing wrong but let me tell
you if you are serious about making 100
crore rupees from stock market never
ever talk to anyone
out of stock market okay
I'm telling this from my own experience
I had started with zero and this amount
is almost uh 80 crore rupees now
lovely
and I had started with zero and if I was
discussing my strategies my trades with
someone else
I could not have made this much of money
you got a point
and Vivek by when you refer uh cagr of
forty percent uh in terms of trading uh
do you account for uh the tax which we
pay 15 or is it post tax free tax or you
disregard the text taxation part because
every time we book a profit there is a
clear
wipe off of that 15 percent tax cut so
15 tax is on the profit whereas whereas
uh for long-term investment only we will
exit only that also where as and when we
kind of you know uh go in for the
selling till then we are not paying tax
actually see I was just wondering I was
just wondering I am holding TCS since
okay so this is the only stock I'm
holding for such a long time
and in that stock even though I'm
holding it since 2008 and this is uh
second largest company in India and it
has been a very good performer of course
we don't have any doubt about it still
the cagr is not even 25 percent
whereas My overall cscr is 47 after
paying taxes during last 17 18 years
the cagr thing you will be tackling in
the next coming sessions I guess
uh calculating the cagr trading curve so
that is very easy that is there is a
form formula and I have shared one
Google sheet yeah but we have not gone
through it you have shared that sheet
but uh somehow I was lost
if you have any question then uh
definitely I'll be clear we can just
take a sample of one or two trades and
just how to track kind of yeah we will
help us
one one more question regarding this cop
and handle and reverse Head and Shoulder
are we to set a gtt for exit prior or
what actually it's better always
and exit you feel we should have some
buffer throughout the some rupees lesser
or you suggest exact uh this thing see
this is just some Davos which come to my
mind it's again a choice if we will be
uh having the buffer and all then
definitely uh they will not have a set
of rules oh correct yeah correct
correct so in your experience always uh
you have taken the price uh whatever I
do I do keep my mind very clear if the
target is 100 let it be 100 okay so
simple okay okay
uh my question is not related to today's
session because I need to again revise
it there and if any outcomes I will come
back to you actually my question is
regarding the previous session
so where you you covered a moving
average uh strategies
um so I have observed in in previous
days that uh sometimes this moving
average the trends uh even in the uh uh
back here it it keeps on changing based
on the uh the current uh the chart
moment
did you ever observe that no see uh
moving average will keep on changing of
course but once you know the package is
made no it will never be changed in the
Bandit no it will not be changed it can
only the intraday setup it will change
exactly intraday it will be changed
because it will be considering intraday
candles
uh but on daily candles it will never be
changed
no never it cannot be changed okay we
can we can take a call on the base of
that okay okay thank you sir one
question sir please yes
um
recommended writer that we have if we
try to purchase it on the opening time
I have never recommended an issue I've
never recommended
for us to purchase so when we try to
purchase going up and up we are not able
to make it so what does strategy I mean
whether we have to execute gtt like that
so that we can purchase on a base price
you need to focus on v40 companies based
on the Learned stats
as I said
to uh perform stunt is not your right
now
right you are at a very early age
right sir right and by utilizing by
applying these strategies those I am
teaching here you will be making
consistent money year on year there's no
need to go on on that
as I told you uh I'm in a different
state
I'm in a different position
a lot of people are relying upon me that
Vivek Bhai will come up with a video so
that we can make some money
right but you don't you don't need to go
for that
in your portfolio at least
stay with me 40 and v40 next companies
and keep on making money
right
yeah thank you can you try out a
telegram uh you are on active on Twitter
but um
so I have you tried exploring a telegram
channel uh for flashing news just as you
do for Twitter still uh the news I am
flashing or I am doing whatever on
social media is no more applicable on my
students those have taken my online
classes
I I have delivered the premium content
to you so the mediocre content you don't
need to have or you don't need to uh
trade in your accounts
right
uh yes
yeah um good evening sir my question is
about V10 strategy and uh I just got the
uh okay one say on rhs and cwh is
applicable we take the V10 once the
price drops from a peak 10 it comes down
right and then the second while
averaging we take it the second uh V10
trade once that drops further five
percent
so my question is when no no sorry 10
from the second Peak yeah and the gap
between now first buying and this this
second buying should be more than five
percent yes correct so what is the
target of the second averaging trade the
very very important the second Peak
the second one not ten percent the
second Peak second week okay
and run so think a for complex rhs then
the first left shoulder is formed and it
touches the neckline and then when it
starts forming the second shoulder is it
mandatory to touch the neckline again
for the second and the third shoulders
as well or if it touches the first left
holder once the right shoulder once the
right shoulder uh has given the breakout
from the base formation
nothing is important after that okay
that is not relevant relief yes answer I
hadn't doubt about uh one chart pattern
in uh as per v20 strategy so sorry may
open Johnson uh Johnson Controls Hitachi
yes so there's one uh trade that is open
uh a long time back since
since long time back this is what you
were saying yeah
it said I shared it with you the
question regarding it was that
so there is a movement of more than 28
percent
um in April yes sir
when the price hit the lower range we
made our first trade yes and Sir right
right here and then said it fell after
that uh when we purchased at the lower
end of the range
10 percent more
down then we purchased it again averaged
it
no
because I want this is my question we
need to buy if there's a here any other
20 movement okay he said if otherwise
we'll just stay with the original
position yes that's it okay
in that case we will not we will not
average the there should be a separate
v20 movement and the trade based on
separate v20 movement should be lower
than 10 percent
okay as we are talking about in V10
I'm asking about v20 yeah means in the
same manner as we did in V10 in the same
manner we need to have a 20 separate
movement as well and the second trade
should be 10 lower than the First Rate
okay otherwise we'll just stay with the
position yes right thank you
this trade is still open uh that trade
is still open that ready is still open
sir
Hitachi control that is making uh
world-class air conditioning air
conditioner AC is uh this company is
going to have a big orders from telecom
companies very soon
because in Telecom Towers Telecom Towers
Telecom operators are having a
preference to Hitachi
for their Telecom towers and because of
the 5G rollout they are going to have a
lot more new towels
batteries and
gchac will be gaining from this momentum
I believe they are sitting on a huge
inventory exactly that's why
they will be selling it now you're so
big
uh hi veggie uh so uh for complex rhs
should we have a multiple uh soldiers on
both the side or any one side also make
it complex on one side also on one side
also
the means on both the side there should
be at least one one shoulder but but on
the one another side on one side
right you got it sorry
yes please
from your background
maybe maybe I'm actually outside okay
okay yes
okay
[Music]
any other question please anyone
I was scanning through HDFC limited uh
for v20 uh there I the registered a 20
plus movement recently but uh candle
week is disproportionately large in one
of the candles so is that okay okay I
have to consider the top of the week to
the bottom of first of all you need to
come upon the uh camera I need to see
okay then give me two minutes I'll just
go you are not wearing a shirt
yeah I mean it was
sir I want to ask you
ask you strategy uh how many trades can
you take I was not clear on that
in V10
yes
based on Wheaton we can take two trades
and one trade based on top with handle
or reverse head and shoulders so total
three trades
clear
thank you I mean at one time you can
take two trades but otherwise you can
take as many as possible no no maximum
three trades in one store
okay uh like you showed some yeah seven
opportunities it means it means we must
not invest more than nine percent in one
stock in any condition please please
note it down at any point of time or
total no total we must not be invested
more than nine percent in one stock in
any condition
in total as well
like if I've taken a cup with handle
which is ongoing and then I take two V10
and that's it I I achieve the Target in
2 week 10 I should not take any I'm in
the open positions of course that's what
I'm saying okay yes I'm in the open
positions open version can be messed yes
yes
answer it would be like um partial
profits
no there is no need to book the partial
profit if the target is achieved uh then
book the full profit if Target is not
achieved then no partially profit like
uh foreign
and another trade we have taken based on
V10 that is three percent and the target
of Wheaton is achieved so we are exiting
from V10 uh trade so this is
so in total yes based on the exclusive
you will be maintaining the Excel sheet
right right
yes
sir can we have in your Excel sheet that
you've given the formulas cannot be um
you know they're blocked although I
tried to do it myself you need you need
to copy
all content as it is press Ctrl a then
Ctrl C
and then control V the following but the
formulas don't come Aditya will help you
in that case okay okay
now this is better at least I must know
how do I show you no no what do you want
to say HDFC I have registered that in
the v20 strategy
uh the bunch of candles which contribute
for to making that we are 20 one of the
week of the candle is disproportionately
uh longer than the body so uh according
to my means according to uh my teaching
uh
from bottom to top you're told and
that's it
disproportionately I was just wondering
no that's it that's okay that's it
thanks
yes anything else please anyone Vivek by
uh good evening how are you I'm good bye
yeah do you like my uh in in some of the
strategy we know that the technical
Target so that we can
um write in Excel sheet work which you
have shared but the uh strategy like
simple moving average and Rob Booker
Knoxville in that case we cannot write
the target we need to regularly watch
that at the end of the day okay so we
cannot get to know how much we need to
get oh no no okay thank you thanks
uh yes
please unmute yourself
can you hear me now yes I can hear so my
name is aravind and actually I am new to
this stock market India so I have to
know a meaning for a word like uh
sometimes called speculative Trading
what sorry second speculative trading so
speculative trading is uh swing trading
basically uh which is not the long term
investing so there are three things uh
one is a long-term investing second is
speculative trading and third one is the
gambling
right so gambling is intraday and future
adoption
right gambling is intraday and featured
an option and integrative trading is
show to medium term trading which is
what we are learning here and long-term
trading is long-term investing is
something we are buying today and we
will not sell it for example as I told
you uh I am holding PCS for last 14
years now
okay
okay okay
yes sir yes
can you uh please refer zensar Tech uh
chart uh is it possible for you what's
in that
uh there is a range I've come across a
46 percent in v20
but uh the price has gone three times
higher and it has not yet touched the
bottom it has gone three or four times
higher and it is coming down but it is
not yet it has not touched the lower
range okay so far so
it's a active trade now because I was
just wondering uh because the the rate
becomes active it becomes active when uh
you take it
there's a range and the price comes down
at the lower line lower level and if and
if the price is not coming at the lower
level this is so this trade is not
active
uh because I was one because you said
that the operator is uh this is not
necessary that every time the price will
come down to the lower Line This is not
necessary we will take a trade if it
will come down if it does come yeah why
I'm asking is the operator may have
already made his profit because the
prices already gone three times plus uh
over and above the range so I was just
wondering if he exits the this rate this
is not necessary that every time if
there is a range of more than 20 price
will come down at lower Line This is not
necessary
if it will come down we will take it
right
okay okay
so operator has not booked this profit
that is our underlying assumption or as
you as you reported it operator might
have booked the profit at a higher level
yeah and he will again take the trade
that is what you had reverted earlier
this is the trade again it's not
necessary
but our lower range is valid we can take
the trade storage is valid yes so lower
range is valid to take a trade if the
price come down
up to 12 months only ah okay because
some I've really gone back so our buying
point so our buying point should be
within 12 months from the 20 movement it
is not enough yeah this year not uh
captured actually please repeat
our buying Point our buying level our
buying date should be within 12 months
from the 20 movement
I guess that it's in the case of Lux
Industries
foreign
Lux Industries is going to give us very
good gains we just need to hold that
and all of you can do one thing
you can invest just 15 000 rupees more
15 17 700 rupees separately in Lux
Industries for one year and the fees of
the classes will be recovered
thank you
the right away tomorrow
sorry you are we can take the plans
tomorrow
yes okay yes you can finally we got the
tip Vivek bye
you will be getting a lot of tips on the
last session don't worry you will get
the you will get the complete portfolio
on the last session oh great great
and by the way you cannot take the trade
tomorrow because tomorrow is off Sunday
without raising the hands you can ask
now
yeah uh I have a question yes please can
you
sir uh you know you you had explained
that the retailer or the operator is
hitting the stop loss is getting the
retailer to hit the stop loss
or is the operator hitting the stop loss
that point is not clear can you show
maintenance
retailers are selling
retailers are selling at the lower price
than their buying price and when someone
is selling at a lower price than the
buying price this is called the stop
loss
so retail public is selling below their
buying price
not the Operator Operator never book a
loss
they don't have a habit to book a loss
they are just like me
so the retailer is hitting the stop loss
yes and the stop loss that um what do
you call it the support is being created
by the operator yes
got it so this is a net this is a net
business
this is a trap that is being created by
The Operators this is a trap now can you
I ask you like in the case of Tata Alexi
for example a deck water two results
were not good and thus uh you know is it
operators doing this that the
stock is falling so much
what's your opinion on that every moment
that is more than 10 in any stock is
being operated by operators only we
retain public don't have too much force
to create
to move a stock either on the upside or
on the downside by more than 10 percent
right
so does this create a
great opportunity then for a retailer if
there is a chartered if this is a good
company if this is a good business if we
are meeting all the conditions based on
any strategy then only otherwise not
only because the stock has come down it
doesn't mean this is a buying
opportunity no
it is not
any other thing hello sir yes this is
rhs suppose the left shoulder is created
and now it's creating the head
and while coming up it didn't touch the
neckline and Below only it came again
down
like for example five ten percent below
only it came down so is it valid or
unvalid
we need to uh witness the base formation
we need to witness the breakout from the
base formation we just need to follow
the condition simple
if this is following the condition then
this is valid if our conditions are not
being met then this is not valid
okay sir
which talk we are talking about
any stock he was taking the hypothetical
example okay okay
good evening good evening sir good
evening this is Divya you know me that
you know I'm a question bank but I don't
have any questions for you now uh I just
unmuted and joined the meeting to wish
you a very very happy birthday thank you
thank you thank you God bless you
same to yourself
good evening sir good evening
this is Monty yes sir first of all
belated happy birthday to you sir thank
you Monty thank you actually sir I am
having a question regarding to wrong
your voice is gone
your question is regarding what
not getting your voice Monty
no not getting your voice
any other question please
if any one of us yeah yes please no I
can hear you
okay son actually I was having the
question regarding Rob Booker Knoxville
Divergence that you have explained the
last day yeah and so in that uh strategy
we have planned that the uptrend lines
that are connecting that top to top
and downtrend lines that are connecting
from bottom to bottom will make the
lines yeah okay so literally I have gone
through some chats and like icigi
um in that chart potential I have seen
that in the lower to lower points uh has
been created but down trending lines are
missing so actually I want to know uh am
I doing any mistake in plotting
can you please uh share the chart on
WhatsApp so that we can understand it
better and we could resolve your
question it will be better okay okay
thank you sir thank you
uh Vivek can knocks will be applied on
Johnson those part of v40 next not v40
no no
everybody was showing by just Finance in
your uh session so the price is always
is already lower than the breakout Point
yes so I we can have one trade for a
dedicated to uh this uh
yeah yeah we can so we can return it
till the
exit exit appointment yes in fact we can
we can have two right uh we can have two
trades
handle we can have two trains yes
having the different targets right yeah
so see you tomorrow
and tomorrow we are going to uh have a
look at the financials
and we will make sure that we don't need
to become a chartered accountant to
understand the financials for trading
purpose
right so uh why I'm saying this I'm
saying that we need to leave a lot of
things untouched while understanding
financials there are very few
information those are really relevant
uh for finding good companies within a
good business
okay I will explain each and everything
it will be a complete three hours long
session after that we might be having uh
q a so uh because I do know it will take
two and half an hour at least to uh uh
explain you each and everything
right and we have early class tomorrow
like instead of eight to eleven like
something like seven to
again everybody's uh
so let it be 8 to 11 plus
I'm already feeling like that uh once I
have rescheduled it and a lot of people
are missing so uh I mean already in a
grilled but uh
I I'll be uh sending a message on the
group again
where are you planning your offline in
gurgaon again or any other City
uh not in any other City uh only in
gurgaon itself
my uh December batch is already full uh
I have seat in January batch
okay might be I need to confirm from
from Aditya whether means how many seats
are available might be two three seats
and usually uh how many days it is and
it is of two days only Saturday Sunday
two or two days Saturday Sunday from
nine o'clock to six o'clock and I do
speaks for uh I do speak for eight hours
continuously without my in front of
everyone
right in a standing position so yeah I
have a good stamina I have not heard
about it and that is with the help of
chanting that is with the help of having
right food and working every day doing
exercise
uh doing everything that is needed to uh
maintain doing everything that is needed
to uh control or in the benefit of
so we have three assets that is the body
physical body second is uh the mind and
third is the money
so whatever we are doing that should be
giving some contribution to uh
building up either giving us more time
giving us uh more uh energy giving us
more knowledge giving us more money or
making our help making our body healthy
these are three assets
and it asks that is not increasing the
strength of these three things is a
useless task
so anytime whatever we are doing if we
can have a question whether this task is
going to increase my money if no is it
increase it is going to increase my
physical health no is it going to
increase my knowledge base no then why
why I'm doing this for what
it means that is a useless task
right
and we should always be a watch why
because we must know what we are going
to do in next one hour
if we if we don't know what we are going
to do in next one hour we are wasting
resource that is most valuable
rich people are buying this by paying
money
we have no right to waste it
rich people are as I had given an
example earlier also rich people are
hiring the chauffeur for their car
because not because they don't like to
drive the car of course they do like but
because they want to have more time so
that in that time they could finish up
their calls they could reply on their
WhatsApp they could fix up the meetings
and they could read something
we need to make the best use of
available time
always always
yes
so I have one question regarding this
batch that you're talking about offline
uh a person needs to do this what we are
learning in this batch right now uh we
need to practice it maybe for a year
before we do this on the batch no if you
are a good student and if you uh see you
need to have acceptance that whatever
Vivek by has got
is actually in your favor and you will
be making money with that that's it
in offline batch I need my loyal people
so simple
people uh means the candidate who wants
to become like me who understand my
ideology who understand my lifestyle who
want to accept me as it is
offline batches for them
tried giving a zoom touch to your
offline also because people sitting uh
so and this is a filter process if
someone is ready to come from uh far
away countries of course they are really
interested and they are loyal
and why I'm fine why I'm searching for
loyal people because uh I want to be
loyal with them it's a army it's a
closed group when we are meeting in
person for two days we have a different
bonding we have a friendship
hey
so those are different uh mints that is
the next label
foreign
what I'm doing uh early in the morning
how I'm going how I'm running how I'm
sleeping what I'm doing what I'm reading
what I'm eating
what I'm chanting why I'm chanting why
I'm eating why I'm drinking everything
how to tackle buaji how to tackle MOSI
how to tackle bhatija how to tackle
sister how to tackle friends how to
tackle uh these colleagues and how to
take 35 percent uh
appraisal every year from your boss
it's everything it's everything
criteria to enter the offline class yes
there are three criterias one uh you
must have taken online course of course
you have taken second uh second uh you
must have time during Market hours I
would say if you don't have time during
Market hours then uh the strategy which
I am teaching here you will be making
money every month no matter where the
market is going you will be making money
every month and the cagr will be more
than 50 you will not be able to use that
if you are not uh full-time
right and third uh the portfolio size
should be at least 40 50 lakhs
so that when when we are making 50 on 40
lakhs it means we are making 20 lakh
rupees a year from that so uh we are
able to uh run our family with that
money
because we are full time at least we
need to replace our minimum salary
that is
okay
and uh I will be uploading the video uh
in the morning uh by 10 o'clock so that
you can revise once
good night